Yaser Keneshloo

Graduate Student Virginia Tech University

March 6, 2017 yaserkl@vt.edu

https://yaserkl.github.io/

Education

Fall 2013 - Current PhD Student in Computer Science, Virginia Tech, USA. Advisor Dr. Naren Ramakrishnan 2010 - 2012 M.Sc. in Software Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Iran 2006 - 2010 **B.E.** in Software Engineering, Shahrood University, Iran

Professional Experience

Virginia Tech Arlington, VA

GRA, Discovery Analytics Center. Advisor: Dr. Naren Ramakrishnan Fall 2014 - Current

- Working on Abstractive News Headline Generation in collaboration with The Washington Post using Attention-Based Encoder-Decoder models. (Current)
- Built a model in *Python* and *R* for forecasting the number of clicks that an article would receive after a day using early signals that we collect from it after 30 minutes of its publication. This model is an online tool, already being used in *The Washington Post* for predicting the popularity of news articles.
- Built a model for forecasting the shape of the news article views and peak time of news article views. This model is at the development phase in The Washington Post and will be implemented and used along side the popularity prediction module.
- Working on prediction of venues daily/weekly wine consumption in collaboration with Sestra Systems. We are building a model for predicting the demand for each venue using a combination of HMM, Regression, and Motif Clustering.
- Analyzed the effect of open source datasets like daily price of commodities from *Premise* and internet traffic on websites from Akamai on predicting the Domestic Political Crisis in Latin America countries.
- Collaborated on an analysis of the network of entrepreneurs on VT campus in Blacksburg and Roanoke area based on the Twitter Follower-Followee network.

Verisign Labs Reston, VA Summer Intern, mentored by Galileo Namata May 2014

- Worked on understanding Corporate Family Trees using community detection on noisy hypergraphs.

Blacksburg, VA Virginia Tech

GTA in Dept. of Computer Science. Instructor: Dr. Cliff Shaffer Fall 2013 - Spring 2014

- Grading and tutoring duties for Data Structure in Java class of ≈ 100 students.

Mobin Research Center

Tehran, Iran

Java Programmer

Summer 2013

- Worked on online clustering and classification of massive news feed streams on a distributed framework using Apache Hadoop, Apache Lucene and Mahout.
- Implemented an online short text clustering in Java based on Wordnet dataset and different text corpuses like news wire corpus.
- Generated the dependency management module of the project using Maven

Wikifegh Tehran, Iran Research Intern Winter 2012

- Querying and mining attributed social networks, Wikifegh social network.
- Implemented a visualization module in *JSP* that can represent the connections among different entities of the network in a more comprehensive way than a database table to the system

$\begin{array}{c} {\rm administrator.} \\ {\bf Security~Operation~Centre~Project} \end{array}$

Tehran, Iran

Researcher

Winter 2011-Winter 2012

- I was part of a team that Designed and Implemented an Intelligent Correlation Engine for the Security Operation Center (SOC) and Investigating the Performance of Correlation Engine and Knowledge Base Altogether.
- Implemented a module for Event Correlation using Frequent Pattern Mining in Data Streams.
- Netbarg.com

Tehran, Iran

Web Developer

Fall 2011

- Implemented the access control module using the ACL (Access Control List)
- Implemented the SMS sender and massive email distribution module using the MailChimp service

Current Project

Research Problem: Abstractive News Headline Generation using Attention-based Encoders

- Application area: Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning
- Frameworks: Keras, Theano, TensorFlow, Python

Research Statement

Research Focus: Data-driven contextual and temporal modeling of news article views to improve user news reading and editors writing experience

- Application area: Time-series prediction, Natural Language Processing
- Broad Focus: Data Mining, Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition.

Publications

2016

2014

Current Publications

1

Y. Keneshloo, S. Wang, E.-H. S. Han, and N. Ramakrishnan. Predicting the shape and peak time of news article views. 2016

Y. Keneshloo, S. Wang, E.-H. Han, and N. Ramakrishnan. Predicting the popularity of news articles. In *Proceedings of the 2016 SIAM International Conference on Data Mining*, pages 441–449. SIAM, 2016

Y. Keneshloo, J. Cadena, G. Korkmaz, and N. Ramakrishnan. Detecting and forecasting domestic political crises: a graph-based approach. In *Proceedings of the 2014 ACM conference on Web science*, pages 192–196. ACM, 2014

Other Publications

Y. Keneshloo and S. Yazdani. A relative feature selection algorithm for graph classification. In *Advances in Databases and Information Systems*, pages 137–148. Springer, 2013

Technical Skills

Programming Python, R, Java, C/C++, Matlab

 ${\tt Javascript,\,Perl,\,HTML/CSS}$

 ${\bf Frameworks}\ {\rm MapReduce},\, {\rm Spark},\, {\rm SQL},\, {\rm Keras}$